siemens-healthineers.com 2019-12-12

# Siemens Healthineers Data Privacy Policy - Siemens Healthineers Global

### Processing of your personal data

Siemens Healthineers processes your personal data as part of your use of our websites and online services as described in the following:

 **Use of the websites**

When using our websites, Siemens Healthineers processes information which is technically necessary for communication to take place and which may also be automatically sent to us by your browser or device, e.g. IP address, device type, browser type, pages visited, date and time of the request.

We process this information in order to enable you to visit the websites, to improve and accelerate the presentation of the websites, to adapt and prepare the information offered for specific target groups and to design the websites according to user preferences.

In addition, we process this information to ensure compliance with our Terms of Use, to exercise or defend ourselves against legal claims, and to prevent and counter fraudulent and similar actions, including attacks on our IT infrastructure.

The legal basis for the processing is the safeguarding of the legitimate interests of Siemens Healthineers as website operator (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR).

 **Subscription of information and participation in surveys**

On our websites you can subscribe to various information, such as subscribe to newsletters or provide us with comments and feedback by participating in surveys. Siemens Healthineers processes the personal data that you have entered via the website, e.g. contact information such as first and last name, e-mail address, telephone number or comments.

Siemens Healthineers uses this personal data to contact you and provide the requested information, to process your comments and feedback and to adapt and prepare the information offered for specific target groups.

The legal basis for the processing is your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR).

 **Use of contact forms and chatbots**

You can contact us directly via contact forms and chatbots on our website and in particular provide your contact details. Siemens Healthineers processes the contact information you provide, such as your first and last name, e-mail address or telephone number, as well as information you provide in a support request, in order to respond to and clarify your contact or request.

The legal basis for the processing is your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR). If your request is aimed at the conclusion of a contract, the legal basis for the processing is the performance of a contract (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR).

 **Online Services**

On our websites you can register for various Siemens Healthineers Online Services by providing your personal data, for example to access technical documents of our products or to exchange information in user forums.

Siemens Healthineers processes the personal data that you have entered when using the Siemens Healthineers Online Services for example when registering or logging in, such as your first and last name, e-mail address, telephone number, comments or forum posts.

Siemens Healthineers processes your personal data,

  * to provide the services and features of the Online Services and to manage your use; or to enable you to use the services and features of the Online Services;
  * to verify your identity and enable user authentication;
  * to ensure compliance with our Terms of Use, establish or defend against legal claims, and prevent fraudulent or similar acts, including attacks on our IT infrastructure.

The legal basis for the processing is your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR), the performance of a contract (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR) or the safeguarding of the legitimate interests of Siemens Healthineers as the provider of online services (Art. 6 para 1 lit. f GDPR).

 **Processing of personal data related to your business relationship with Siemens Healthineers**

In the context of a business relationship with Siemens Healthineers, we process personal data of contact persons at customers, interested parties, sales partners, suppliers and partners ("business partners"). For further information, please refer to the Siemens Healthineers Privacy Policy for Business Partners at the bottom of the page under "Downloads".
